Register of the Ermil Glink, Pseud., Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ermil Glink, pseud., papers,
1950-1967
2000C59
Glink, Ermil, pseud.
3 microfilm reels (0.45 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings and correspondence, relating to political conditions in the Soviet Union and to anti-communist movements in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Biographical Note
Russian émigré in the United States.
Scope and Content Note
The true name of the author of these writings and correspondence is unknown - several possibilities can be gleaned from the writings, but Ermil Glink, though an obvious pseudonym, has been chosen as the main entry because it is the most prevalent (other options are N. Ch., Vasilii Labutin, and N. Panchenko, the last of which may be his real name). The writings are largely autobiographical and anti-Communist, describing the author's experiences in the Soviet Union up to the 1940s.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco, as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Soviet Union--Politics and government.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; Russians--United States.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation).; United States--Politics and government.; Communism.
Series Description
- Correspondence, 1950-1953. (Box 1)
  Drafts of letters to the President of the United States, Congressmen and other political figures, and correspondence with the American Committee for the Liberation of the Peoples of Russia
- Writings, 1950-1967. (Box 1-3)
  Arranged chronologically by title. Includes associated correspondence
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1950-1953 (Box 1)
  - General - Drafts of letters to the President of the U.S., Congressmen, and other political figures, relating to the struggle against Communism, 1950-1952 (Folder 1: 1)
  - American Committee for the Liberation of the Peoples of Russia, 1952-1953 (Folder 1: 2)
- WRITINGS, 1950-1967.
  Includes associated correspondence
  - "Rasskaz prostogo cheloveka," 1950. (Folder 1: 3)
    Holograph
  - "V tiskakh: Zapiski russkago emigranta," 1950-1967. (Folder 1: 4-7)
    Typescript. Musings and reminiscences, compiled over seventeen years. Includes associated correspondence
  - "V tiskakh" (Box-folder 2: 1-6)
  - "V tiskakh" (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "Chto dielaet russkii muzhik v emigratsii: Tri miesiatsa v Amerikie," 1953. (Folder 3: 2)
    Typescript
  - "Pis'mo prostogo cheloveka," 1953. (Folder 3: 3)
  - "Chem i kak my zhili, ili tak chto-zhe takoe kommunizm v zhizni," [1954]. (Folder 3: 4)
  - "Zhiteiskie rasskazy: Vosem' let za koliuchei provolokoi," 1955. (Folder 3: 5)
  - "Smeisia dusha: Russkiia anekdoty," 1967. (Folder 3: 6)